Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ chenwang1364 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Strategic Partnerships
Python
Machine Learning

Languages

Japanese (Elementary)
Spanish (Elementary)
English (Native or Bilingual)
Chinese (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Problem Framing for Al

DataRobot Time Series Modeling

DataRobot for Data Scientists

Particulate Media: From Fundamentals to Applications, From Granular Media to Colloids and Active Matter

DataRobot Al Modeling Techniques

Honors-Awards

MacCracken Fellowship
Best Teaching Assistant
International Conference Scholarship
Front Cover Article
Themed Collection: Celebrating Soft

Publications

Holographic characterization of colloidal fractal aggregates

Matter's 10th Anniversary

Celebrating Soft Matter's 10th Anniversary: Monitoring colloidal growth with holographic microscopy

Stimulus-responsive colloidal sensors with fast holographic readout

Chen Wang

Enterprise GenAl

New York, New York, United States

Summary

Data Scientist, Strategy Consultant and Sales Engineer with PhD in Physics, strong ML expertise in creating AI vision, building AI solutions to deliver business value, incorporate more intelligence and automation into business process and accelerate digital transformation with Enterprise Machine Learning Platform.

Experience

Al21 Labs

Lead Alliance Solution Architect December 2023 - Present (9 months)

New York City Metropolitan Area

Generative AI for enterprise with partners and customers

DataRobot

4 years 4 months

Director of Applied AI, Alliances & Channel Partnership February 2023 - December 2023 (11 months)

New York City Metropolitan Area

Drive demand generation, customer adoption and value creation through tech alliances ecosystem, global system integrators and channel service providers in enterprise AI.

Product integration, joint solution development and GTM with all major cloud partners.

Develop joint partner solutions and marketing events to drive quality leads. Retrieval-Augmented Generative AI solution development with cloud and service partners.

Customer Facing Data Science Practice, Channel Partnership Americas Lead

February 2021 - January 2023 (2 years)

New York City Metropolitan Area

Holographic characterization of protein aggregates

Patents

In-Line Particle Characterization Holographic characterization of protein aggregates Lead and build the Data Science Practice using DataRobot Enterprise Al Platform for partner ecosystem in Americas.

Deliver business value for customers through partner co-sell play and professional services delivery.

Scale the business rapidly and effectively by building up the DataRobot partner ecosystem for joint GTM.

Enable service provider partners with DataRobot platform and improve their Al service capability.

Execution Data Scientist September 2019 - January 2021 (1 year 5 months) Greater New York City Area

Develop complex end-to-end enterprise-grade data and AI solution with DataRobot for customers across industry verticals, to digitally transform their business with our AI platform, industry solution and technical know-how.

Predicting COVID-19 on the U.S. county level:

https://www.datarobot.com/covid-19-prediction/

https://www.datarobot.com/blog/predicting-the-covid-19-on-the-u-s-county-level/

IBM

2 years 6 months

Lead Data Scientist/Managing Strategy Consultant, Chief Analytics Office

February 2019 - September 2019 (8 months)

Greater New York City Area

Develop ML solution and advance analytical model for IBM internal business operation strategy.

Lead a team of data scientists, machine learning engineers and strategy consultants to develop a customer churn prediction solution by time series classification and deep learning model with best next action recommendations for SaaS client success team

Develop ML based dynamic pricing prediction tool for world-wide deployment to all IBM sellers with tens of millions dollars revenue improvement each year. Presented to Senior VP regularly.

Guide a team of MBA students from the University of Notre Dame to complete their Capstone project sponsored by IBM to develop a product review sentiment analysis tool using NLP and D3 visualizations for offering managers.

Lead and develop multiple career development programs

Run the data challenge for IBM data scientist recruiting program used to evaluate the machine learning modeling skills for hundreds of data scientist candidates.

Senior Strategy Consultant/Senior Data Scientist, Chief Analytics Office April 2017 - February 2019 (1 year 11 months) Armonk, NY

Eminence and Excellence Award, 2017

Eminence and Excellence Award - Cognitive Champion, 2018

Manager's Choice Award - Dare to Create Original Ideas, 2018

Manager's Choice Award - Unite to Get It Done Now, 2018

First place of IBM CAO Hackathon, 2018

Center for Soft Matter Research, New York University 4 years 7 months

Research Assistant January 2013 - March 2017 (4 years 3 months) Greater New York City Area

Statistical physics modeling and holographic characterization of mutable colloidal systems

Front Cover and Selected Collection on Soft Matter 2014
Featured Article on Journal of Pharmaceutical Sciences: 2016

Teaching Assistant
September 2012 - August 2013 (1 year)
Greater New York City Area

Teaching Assistant for General Physics I and II, lab and recitation, over 120 students in total

Best Teaching Assistant in Physics Department, 2012

Page 3 of 4

Education

New York University

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.), Physics · (2011 - 2017)

Nanjing University
Bachelor's Degree, Physics · (2007 - 2011)